Daniel Silva

Cutler Bay, FL 33190 ● (305) 505-9150 ● daniel@silvanolte.com

https://medium.com/@danielsweb

Professional Summary

Emerging technology executive that loves building and leading teams that use technology to solve business problems. I can transform your organization and prepare it for today and the future. I have over 20 years of experience serving in the following industries: Payments, Supply Chain, Intelligence, Defense, Hospitality, Food Service, and Health and Wellness.

Skills

- Leadership and Management
- Team building/culture
- Agile methodologies
- Product mindset

- Technology strategy
- Cloud strategy
- Budgeting
- Security and Risk Management

Work History

Chief Information Officer, 10/2019 to Current

Independent Purchasing Cooperative Inc. - Miami, FL

- Responsible for Corporate IT, Application Development, Product Ownership, and Security and Risk management for the company
- Key achievements: Transitioned credit/debit processing from an in-house solution to an external vendor (Adyen), and led the internalization of trading partner data ingestion to give our company visibility into the SubwayTM supply chain
- Set the technical vision, mission, and priorities for the company
- Ensured that the Technology department was appropriately staffed to accomplish the mission
- Developed the culture and processes that ensure the organization is continuously generating value
- Evolved the organizational structure of the Technology department to serve the culture and mission best; staying ahead of the curve, identifying opportunities for technology innovation
- Developed Directors and Managers so that they can properly lead and manage their groups within the organization
- Collaborated with the other organizational heads as an advisor of all technology needs of the organization
- Ensured that Engineers apply technology standards and best practices

Chief Technology Officer, 03/2019 to 10/2019

Independent Purchasing Cooperative Inc. - Miami, FL

- Created the technology vision and strategy for the company
- Managed company-level architecture, platform and data configuration processes and

- implementation protocols
- Facilitated ongoing team development and growth through training and professional skills enhancement
- Maintained high-level knowledge of current and emerging technology development and applications
- Coordinated third-party vendors and client IT teams to seamlessly deliver effective solutions
- Ensured technology systems and procedures met overall company priorities
- Researched new technologies and chose best options for company priorities and cost-effectiveness

Chief Technology Officer, 02/2017 to 03/2019

PLXIS (Independent Purchasing Cooperative Inc.) – Miami, FL

- Created technology vision and strategy for new startup subsidiary of Independent Purchasing Cooperative Inc., surrounding its payments platform.
- Key achievements: commercialization of payments platform, payments terminal solution
- Managed company-level architecture, platform and data configuration processes and implementation protocols
- Facilitated ongoing team development and growth through training and professional skills enhancement
- Maintained high-level knowledge of current and emerging technology development and applications
- Coordinated third-party vendors and client IT teams to seamlessly deliver effective solutions
- Ensured technology systems and procedures met overall company priorities
- Researched new technologies and chose best options for company priorities and cost-effectiveness

Director of Application Development, 01/2013 to 02/2017

Independent Purchasing Cooperative Inc. - Miami, FL

- Worked closely with management teams to plan, develop, coordinate and execute technical strategies aligned to client's vision, mission and purpose
- Key achievements: MySubwayCard.com Subway™ gift card management web site supporting over 4 million guests, Subway™ consumer loyalty program, Subway™ digital offers, and PayPal and Masterpass payment integration
- Guided implementation of company-wide enterprise security strategy for network and hardware, disaster recovery, data protection and endpoint protection
- Oversaw development and implementation of improvements to software engineering practices, alerting and monitoring, and operational intelligence

Senior Software Engineer, 01/2010 to 01/2013

Interval International – Miami, FL

- Responsible for writing, testing, deployment, and operations of custom software development
- Key achievements: architecture, implementation and deployment of the central operations system providing inventory, membership and exchange services
- Technologies used: Java, J2EE, Groovy, Grails, MySQL, Oracle 10i RDBMS, PL/SQL, JBoss 4,

JBoss BPM, BPEL, SOA, SOAP, XML, Mule, HTML and JavaScript (JQuery)

- Tested troubleshooting methods, devised innovative solutions, and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team use
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns

Education

Some College (No Degree): Language Arts Education **Florida International University** - Miami, FL